

# **Yonas Kifle**

**Nationality:** Eritrean

(+31) 685062387

**Date of birth:** 23/06/1987

Gender: Male

Email address: yonney3124@gmail.com

C

Whatsapp Messenger: www.whatsapp.com

in LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com

Add ss: Capelle aan den ijssel, 2903LD Capelle aan den ijssel (Netherlands)

#### **ABOUT ME**

My name is Yonas Kessete Kifle, born in Eritrea. I studied Bachelor's degree in Civil Engineering in Eritrea. After graduation, I worked as an engineer in Eritrea; then, I left my country and worked as an engineer in South Sudan and Angola due to political and safety issues. Finally, I migrated to the Netherland in 2018. Now I have a five-year residence permit, which will be furthered to nationality in the end, as I already did the integration course for the Dutch language. Then I furthered my studies into a master's level in the Netherlands at Utrecht University. I recently graduated with a WO master in Environmental Science specializing in water science and management.

## Hobbies

Travelling, walking, running, cycling, watching love films, listening to slow music, reading, and working.

#### **EDUCATION**

## 1. WO Master in Water Science and Management

*Utrecht University* [02/09/2019 – 31/08/2021]

Address: Heidelberglaan 8, 3584 CS Utrecht (Netherlands)

**Field(s) of study:** Environmental Science (Water Science and Management)

**Final grade:** 7.05/10

## 2. WO Bachelor in Civil Engineering

**Eritrean Institute of Technology** [01/09/2006 – 29/06/2011]

**Address:** Asmara (Eritrea)

Field(s) of study: Civil Engineering

Final grade: 3.3/4

#### TRAINING

#### 1. HTML, CSS, Javascript, python, web developer

**Matrix Master Rotterdam** [14/03/2022 - 10/06/2022]

**Address: Rotterdam** (Netherlands)

## 2. Dutch Language Course (B-2)

**Master Class Dutch Rotterdam** [27/01/2022 - 07/04/2022]

**Address: Rotterdam** (Netherlands)

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

#### 1. Researcher Intern

Netherlands Environmental Assessment Agency (Planbureau voor de Leefomgeving, PBL) [22/02/2021 – 19/07/2021]

**City:** The Hague **Country:** Netherlands

I contributed to the main project called "Future Water Challenges II" by observing "Managed Aquifer Recharge assessment over Sub-Saharan Africa under the present pressures and the future challenges" as a thesis project for culminating my Master's study.

#### 2. Student Consultant

World Waternet Amsterdam

[01/09/2020 - 07/11/2020]

**City:** Amsterdam **Country:** Netherlands

As part of the master's course, we did group work as a transdisciplinary case study for the World Waternet Amsterdam project. The project was about "Decreasing Water Demand via Water Conservation and Water Demand Management Measures in Nairobi, Kenya." It was a successful project full of practical recommendations to tackle the problem of water scarcity in Nairobi, Kenya.

## 3. Engineer, Sales and Stock manager

#### Every Where Angola Limitada

[10/06/2014 - 09/06/2017]

City: Luanda Country: Angola

- 1. Stock auditor and Sales Manager of the Five sister companies (Every Where Angola LDA, Naval General Trading Company, Oceano Trading Company, Vistar Trading Company, and Yawaba General Trading Company containing 41 stores and five sales points).
- 2. Designing and Supervising building of Baby diaper factory, including six big stores and G+2 residential buildings.
- 3. Designing and Supervising building of PVC factory, including G+1 residential building.

#### 4. Civil Engineering Designer and Supervisor

#### **Private**

[01/12/2013 - 05/06/2014]

City: Juba

Country: South Sudan

- 1. Supervising building of a three-story Gemtel building in Juba.
- 2. Designing and supervising building of a two-story building.

#### 5. Civil engineer

**Zoba Debub Administration, Department of Engineering Services and Project Management** [01/09/2011-24/07/2013]

City: Mendefera Country:

Eritrea

- 1. Construction of standard schools through community participation (CP)
- **2.** Construction and Rehabilitation of 30 Hand-dug Stonemasonry Wells in remote areas.
- 3. Construction of Water Supply and Sanitary Projects.
- **4.** Maintenance work for existing buildings.
- **5.** Designing Residential and Commercial buildings.

Duties and responsibilities include:

- This includes architectural, structural designs for residential and commercial buildings, sanitary and water supply structures.
  - Supervise, monitor, and manage different projects.
  - Preparing Planning & coordinating construction projects to complete within the Scheduled time.
  - Preparing take-off sheets and payments to estimate the executed project in time.
  - $\circ$  The estimation of the materials required and managing proper material use on site.
  - Prepare a periodical report on work progress.

## **JOB-RELATED DIGITAL SKILLS**

#### **Job-related skills**

MS Project, Auto CAD, ArchiCAD 15, Staad Pro, Proken, ACI, MS Word, Excel, and PowerPoint, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Hydrus, Imod software, PCR-GLOBWB, Focus.

## **LANGUAGE SKILLS**

Mother tongue(s):

**Tigrignya:** Mother Language **English:** Higher Proficient

Dutch: B2

Amharic: Basic
Portuguese: Basic